John Lee

Software Developer & New Media Artist

Phone +358 (0)46 528 7808

E-mail lee.cheongun@aalto.fi

Home page https://delphi1004.github.io/portfolio/

GitHub https://github.com/delphi1004

I am a student at Aalto University, majoring in New media design and production. Before I came to Finland, I was a software developer for almost 10 years of fully automated metrology (Overlay measurement and AFM) equipment and an MES system for the semiconductor industry. Back then, my main languages were C, C++(MFC), C# and Pro*C(for UNIX server). In addition, I am a fan of physical computing and interactive, generative media art. I'm looking for creative projects and want to work with passionate people.

SKILLS

C, C++, C#, Objective-C, Swift, JavaScript, React, React Native Unity 3D, Processing, openFrameworks, OpenCV Design Software Architecture, Physical Computing Design & Implementation of Interactive Media Art installation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apr 2010 - Feb 2016

System Architect AppStars

South Korea

- iOS developer in Objective-C
- Designed system architecture
- Natural Sound
 - https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id744956026

Sep 2006 - Mar 2010

Senior Developer Triant Technologies

South Korea, Canada

- Integrated FDC(Fault Detection & Classification) system in C#
- Developed a system for customer's needs
- · Developed communication module in Tibco library

Dec 2005 - Sep 2006

Senior Developer Nippo

- Developed FDC System in C#
- · Designed system architecture for FDC system

Sep 2001 - Feb 2003

Senior Developer Silicon and Systems South Korea

- Designed software architecture for automated AFM(Atomic Force Microscopy)
- Implemented equipment control software in Borland C++ builder

Dec 1999 - Sep 2001

Senior Developer Nanometrics South Korea, The US

- Developed software for wafer metrology equipment in VC++
- Experienced with Secs/Gem(Semiconductor's equipment interface protocol)

Sep 1996 - Feb 1998

Junior Developer Mirero System South Korea

- Developed SEM(Scanning Electron Microscope) image management system
- Experienced with Borland Delphi (Object-Pascal)

EDUCATION

Aug 2017 - Present

Aalto University Finland

• Master's programme in New Media Design and Production

Mar 2014 - Feb 2016

Dongguk University

South Korea

Japan

- Master of Engineering
- Major in Convergence Contents Production
- · Hand tracking projection mapping project
 - https://youtu.be/yYf2Ssi9EQA

Coursera Verified Certificates

Online Course

· Introduction to Computational Arts

Mar 2001 - Aug 2007

Korea Digital University

South Korea

- · Bachelor of Engineering
- · Major in Computer and Information Science

Feb 1998 - July 1998

Unitec New Zealand

Completion of Carrington United Language School

PROJECTS & EXHIBITIONS

Aug 2018 - Present

Helsinki Children's Hospital Installation Group Finland

- · Digital aquarium project, Helsinki
 - https://youtu.be/FRKkWGA_GOs https://youtu.be/KFxfdGawWyI

26 May - 31 May 2019

When Light Echoes

Group South Korea

Finland

- Interactive installation exhibition, Seoul
 - https://youtu.be/2yZoM1qjo9o http://whenlightechoes.aalto.fi

23 Feb - 03 Mar 2019

Seeing Sound, Listening to Image Solo

- · Sound visualization exhibition, Väre gallery V1 Aalto University
 - https://youtu.be/3yvqrAyYy-4

Drawing Machine

Solo

South Korea

- Digital fabrication exhibition, IDAS Hong-Ik University, Seoul
 - https://youtu.be/mVPDrrjWDYY

PUBLICATIONS

13 Dec 2017

Tangible Visualization Table for Intuitive Data Display Symmetry MDPI

- https://www.mdpi.com/2073-8994/9/12/316

26 Jun 2016

Hand Tracking Based Projection Mapping System andJ. of KCGS **Applications**

- http://www.kci.go.kr/kciportal/landing/article.kci?arti_id=ART002142333